refind.com 2019-06-02

# Privacy – Refind

All data is securely stored in a Postgres database hosted on [Heroku](https://www.heroku.com/).

We offer optional browser extensions for Chrome, Safari, and Firefox—Refind is fully functional without.

## Browser button

Our browser button allows you to save links to Refind. You can choose to save a link privately or publicly. [Learn more](https://refind.com/about/button)

## Google Search

Refind offers an optional integration with Google search. If you have it enabled, it highlights links you or your friends saved when you search on Google. [Learn more](https://refind.com/about/google-search)

If you have it enabled (opt-in), the extension sends a request to our servers when you search on Google, and our servers respond with the best match. You can disable it in the [settings](https://refind.com/settings).

We do **not** track or store these requests.

## New Tab

New Tab is a separate extension available for Chrome. It shows your Refind feed every time you open a new tab in Chrome. [Learn more](https://refind.com/about/newtab)

## Incognito / Private Mode

All extensions are **disabled** in **Incognito/Private Mode**.

We allow you to connect third-party services. When connecting, we only ask for minimal permissions required to provide our service to you.

## Twitter

You can sign up for Refind with your Twitter account. Refind only asks for **read** permission (thus, it **cannot** post on your behalf). It fetches your profile (name, photo, etc.) in order to create your Refind profile, and the list of people you follow on Twitter in order to connect you with your friends on Refind.

Optionally, you can also import links from your Tweets.

## Facebook

You can sign up for Refind with your Facebook account. Refind asks for minimal permissions. It fetches your profile (name, photo, etc.) to create your Refind profile, and the list of friends that are already on Refind to connect you with.

Optionally, you can also import links from your Tweets.

## Pocket

Optionally you can connect Pocket to import your links into your private reading list. Optionally you can let Refind automatically save links you favorited on Pocket. Refind only asks for **read** permission.

## Buffer

Optionally you can connect Buffer to share your links on social media. Refind requires **write** permission in order to add your links to the Buffer queue. [Learn more](https://refind.com/about/automation)

## General information

This policy sets out our privacy practices and explains how we handle the information we collect when you visit and use our sites, services, mobile applications, products, and content ("Services").

## What data we may collect

We collect information about what Refind pages you access, information about your mobile device (such as device or browser type), information you send us (such as an email address used to register or communicate with us), and referral information.

In order to personalize your feed, we update the hashtags you’re interested in based on your usage of Refind. You can see what data we learned and derived based on your usage on your [hashtags page](https://refind.com/i/following/hashtags) by clicking on **History**. You can control and correct this information to improve your feed. Also, we derive what languages you want to see content in based on your interaction. You can find your language settings [here](https://refind.com/i/following/languages).

When you use Refind, we may collect and store your Internet Protocol address. We may use this information to fight spam and other abuse; to personalize Refind; or to generate aggregate, non-identifying information about how people use Refind.

When you create your Refind account, and authenticate via a third-party service like Twitter or Facebook, we may collect, store, and periodically update the contact lists associated with that third-party account, so you can connect with existing contacts from that service who are on Refind.

## Email from Refind

Sometimes we’ll send administrative emails about account or service changes, or new policies. You can’t opt out of them. You can always opt out of non-administrative emails such as digests—you can opt out of all or individual emails on the [email settings page](https://refind.com/settings/notifications/email).

We won’t email you to ask for your password or other account information. If you receive such an email, send it to us so we can investigate.

## Disclosure of your information

As a rule, we don’t share your personal information outside the company. We won’t sell your personal information.

We may share your personal information with third parties in limited circumstances, including: (1) with your consent; (2) to a vendor or partner who meets our data protection standards; or (3) when we have a good faith belief it is required by law, such as pursuant to a subpoena or other legal process.

If we’re going to share your information in response to legal process, we’ll give you advance notice so you can challenge it (for example by seeking court intervention), unless we’re prohibited from doing so by law or court order. We will object to requests for information about users of our site that we believe to be improper.

If we merge with another company such that your information will become subject to a different privacy policy, we’ll notify you before the transfer. You can opt out of the new policy by deleting your account during the notice period.

## Cookies

We use cookies to recognize you when you return to our Services. We use them in various ways, for example to log you in or to remember your preferences.

Some third-party services that we use, such Google Analytics, may place their own cookies in your browser. This Privacy Policy covers use of cookies by Refind only and not the use of cookies by third parties.

## Data storage

Refind uses third-party vendors and hosting partners, such as Heroku, Amazon S3, Cloudinary, for hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology we need to run Refind. We maintain two types of logs: server logs and event logs.

## Modifying your personal information

If you have a Refind account, you can access and modify your personal information, or delete your account on the [settings page](https://refind.com/settings). Also, you can update your profile on your own profile page.

## Deleting your account

You can delete your account on the [settings page](https://refind.com/settings). If you delete your account, all of your content will be permanently deleted. To protect information from accidental or malicious destruction, we may not immediately delete residual copies from our active servers and may not remove information from our backup systems.

## Exporting your data

You can export your data using our [export tool](https://refind.com/i/import).

## Data security

We use encryption (HTTPS/TLS) to protect data transmitted to and from our site. However, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure, so we can’t guarantee security. You use the Service at your own risk, and you’re responsible for taking reasonable measures to secure your account (like using a strong password).

## Changes to this Policy

Refind may periodically update this Policy. We’ll notify you about significant changes to it. The most current version of the policy will always be here.

## Attribution

This Privacy Policy is greatly inspired by [Medium’s](https://medium.com/policy/medium-privacy-policy-f03bf92035c9).

Questions? Let us know at [hello@refind.com](mailto:hello@refind.com)

    Refind Inc.  
    c/o Dominik Grolimund  
    Rainstrasse 38c  
    8808 Pfaeffikon SZ  
    Switzerland
    
    Company registered in Switzerland under CHE-322.432.450
